[
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old woman from a nursing home presents to the Emergency Department with abdominal pain and vomiting. On examination, she is dehydrated, and her abdomen is distended. There is a 3 x 4 cm swelling in her right groin which is non-tender, and there is no cough impulse. At operation, a femoral Hernia found. Which of the following lies medial to the neck of the hernia?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral artery",
        "Option 2":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Femoral vein",
        "Option 4":"Lacunar ligament",
        "Option 5":"Pectineal ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Lacunar ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which one of me following muscles is an extensor of the hip?",
        "Option 1":"Adductor longus",
        "Option 2":"Gracilis",
        "Option 3":"Iliopsoas",
        "Option 4":"Pectineus",
        "Option 5":"Semitendinosus",
        "Correct Answer":"Semitendinosus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56-year-old man with chronic emphysema is on the high dependency unit (HDU), ten days after anterior resection. He has developed acute shortness of breath and hypotension. Which of the following landmarks would be the most appropriate to use to obtain a femoral arterial blood gas sample?",
        "Option 1":"A point midway between the anterior superior iliac spine and the pubic tubercle",
        "Option 2":"A point midway between the anterior superior iliac-spine and the pubic symphysis",
        "Option 3":"A point midway between the greater trochanter and the pubic symphysis",
        "Option 4":"A point 1cm interior and 4 cm lateral to the pubic tubercle",
        "Option 5":"A point 2 cm lateral to the midway point between the anterior superior iliac spine",
        "Correct Answer":"A point midway between the anterior superior iliac-spine and the pubic symphysis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After receiving an intramuscular Injection in the buttock, a 25-year-old man complains of inability to evert his foot. Which nerve is most likely to have been injured?",
        "Option 1":"Common peroneal (fibular) component of sciatic",
        "Option 2":"Inferior gluteal",
        "Option 3":"Superficial peroneal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superior gluteal",
        "Option 5":"Tibial component of sciatic",
        "Correct Answer":"Common peroneal (fibular) component of sciatic"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45-year-old man presented with backache and leg pain due to prolapsed lumbar intervertebral disc The pain radiates to the dorsum of the foot. On examination, there is weakness of the dorsiflexion of the foot Which nerve root is most likely to be involved?",
        "Option 1":"T12",
        "Option 2":"L3",
        "Option 3":"L5",
        "Option 4":"S1",
        "Option 5":"S2",
        "Correct Answer":"L5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 21-year-old man has been stabbed in the back of the knee, dividing the popliteal artery, and  is undergoing repair via a posterior approach. Which of the following structures is most likely  to be encountered first, when dissecting deep from the skin incision?",
        "Option 1":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 2":"Popliteus muscle",
        "Option 3":"Popliteal vein",
        "Option 4":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Soleus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Tibial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year-old man undergoes a right inguinal hernia repair under general anaesthetic as a day  case patient. He has a nerve block after the procedure. On recovery he has weakness of the  right leg. Which nerve has been affected?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Lateral cutaneous nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Sciatic nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In the posterolateral approach to a posterior malleolar fracture, an incision is made between  the calcinieal Achilles tendon and the distal fibula. Which of the following structures is at risk?",
        "Option 1":"Deep peroneal (fibular) nerve",
        "Option 2":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 3":"Superficial peroneal (fibular) nerve",
        "Option 4":"Sural nerve",
        "Option 5":"Tibial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Sural nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 33-year-eld man presents to the orthopaedic outpatient clinic with a six-month history of low back pain radiating to the lateral aspect of the left upper thigh. Micturition and defecation are normal and there is no history of previous Injury. On examination, left lateral flexion of the spine is limited but a full range of hip movements are observed, although it is painful. Sensation 's altered over the front of the knee. Left knee reflex is reduced. Which spinal nerve is most Likely to have been compressed?",
        "Option 1":"L1",
        "Option 2":"L2",
        "Option 3":"L3",
        "Option 4":"L4",
        "Option 5":"L5",
        "Correct Answer":"L3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with lost sensation over the medial aspect of the leg following a surgery for the varicose veins. What is the root value of the affected nerve?",
        "Option 1":"L2,3",
        "Option 2":"L3,4",
        "Option 3":"L5",
        "Option 4":"L5-S1",
        "Option 5":"S1,2",
        "Correct Answer":"L3,4"
    },
    {
        "Question":"On an ultrasound scan of the popliteal fossa for investigating a swelling, which of the following  structures is closest to the capsule of the knee joint?",
        "Option 1":"Great saphenous vein",
        "Option 2":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 3":"Popliteal vein",
        "Option 4":"Short saphenous vein",
        "Option 5":"Tibial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Popliteal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old man undergoes transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBT). The tumor  lies over the lateral side wall of the bladder just above the opening of the right ureteric orifice  Use of the diathermy suddenly causes the patient to \"kick\" because of contraction of the hip  adductors muscles. Which nerve has been stimulated?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Lateral femoral cutaneous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Obturator nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 25-year-old man is playing football when he complains of posterior thigh pain whilst  sprinting with the ball, On examination he has tenderness in the lower lateral posterior thigh.  He is unable to fully extend the knee due to pain. What is the most likely injury?",
        "Option 1":"Biceps femoris tear",
        "Option 2":"Gracilis tear",
        "Option 3":"Gastrocnemius tear",
        "Option 4":"Semimembranosus tear",
        "Option 5":"Semitendinosus tear",
        "Correct Answer":"Biceps femoris tear"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During recovery from varicose veins surgery, a 35 years old woman complains of weakness of dorsiflexion of the ankle. Physical examination reveals absent sensation over the dorsum of the foot. Which of the following nerves is most likely injured?",
        "Option 1":"Common peroneal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Deep peroneal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superficial peroneal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sural nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Common peroneal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which structure is the deepest in the posterior compartment of leg?",
        "Option 1":"Tibial artery",
        "Option 2":"Fibular artery",
        "Option 3":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 4":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 5":"Tibialis posterior muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Tibialis posterior muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 36-year-old man presents with a two-month history of low back pain radiating to his left leg. After clinical examination, he is referred for an MRI scan. This shows a prolapsed Intervertebral disc. The clinical signs are consistent with pressure on S1 roots. Which combination of clinical signs is most likely?",
        "Option 1":"Weak ankle plantar flexion, altered sensation on the dorsum of the foot and normal ankle jerk reflex",
        "Option 2":"Weak ankle plantar flexion altered sensation on the sole of the foot and loss of ankle jerk reflex.",
        "Option 3":"Weak hallux dorsiflexion altered sensation on the anterior surface of the leg and loss-of ankle jerk reflex.",
        "Option 4":"Weak hallux dorsiflexion altered sensation on the dorsum of the foot and normal ankle jerk reflex.",
        "Option 5":"Weak hallux dorsiflexion, altered sensation on the sole of the foot and loss of knee jerk  reflex",
        "Correct Answer":"Weak ankle plantar flexion altered sensation on the sole of the foot and loss of ankle jerk reflex."
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 24-year-old man is assaulted and sustains a deep 2 cm long laceration to the lateral aspect of his lower leg Physical examination shows that the laceration is anterior to the lateral malleolus. Which of the following structures is most at risk of being divided?",
        "Option 1":"Peroneus brevis",
        "Option 2":"Peroneus longus",
        "Option 3":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superficial peroneal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sural nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial peroneal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with fracture of tibia and above knee cast was applied. He later presented with pain on passive plantar flexion of the great toe. Other compartments were normal. Which of the corresponding areas will have paraesthesia?",
        "Option 1":"Dorsum of foot",
        "Option 2":"Lateral border of foot",
        "Option 3":"1st web space",
        "Option 4":"Medial border of foot",
        "Option 5":"Sole of the foot.",
        "Correct Answer":"1st web space"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Sinus Tarsi is an important landmark located between which 2 bones?",
        "Option 1":"Talus and calcaneum",
        "Option 2":"Talus and navicular",
        "Option 3":"Calcaneum and navicular",
        "Option 4":"Navicular and the metatarsals",
        "Option 5":"Navicular and cuneiforms",
        "Correct Answer":"Talus and calcaneum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following statement is true regarding femoral canal?",
        "Option 1":"Pectineal fascia forms the medial border",
        "Option 2":"The inguinal ligament of posteriorly",
        "Option 3":"The lateral border is formed by femoral vein",
        "Option 4":"The lacunar ligament forms lateral border",
        "Option 5":"Fascia iliaca is posteriorly",
        "Correct Answer":"The lateral border is formed by femoral vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structure passes above the piriformis in the greater sciatic notch?",
        "Option 1":"Inferior gluteal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superior gluteal artery",
        "Option 5":"Nerve to obturator internus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior gluteal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man developed lost eversion after a complex ankle injury. Upon examination, where would  you expect site of sensory loss?",
        "Option 1":"1st  web space",
        "Option 2":"Whole dorsum of the foot",
        "Option 3":"Dorsum of the foot except 1st  web space",
        "Option 4":"Lateral aspect of the foot",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Dorsum of the foot except 1st  web space"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man suffered an injury to the back of his knee. On exploring the popliteal fossa, what is the  muscle that forms the superolateral boundary?",
        "Option 1":"Soleus muscle",
        "Option 2":"Gastrocnemius muscle",
        "Option 3":"Biceps femoris muscle",
        "Option 4":"Semitendinosus",
        "Option 5":"Rectus femoris muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Biceps femoris muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 23 years old patient complains from loss of sensation at great toe after foot trauma. What  is the spinal level of the affected area?",
        "Option 1":"L4-5",
        "Option 2":"L3-4",
        "Option 3":"L2-3",
        "Option 4":"S1 only",
        "Option 5":"S2-2",
        "Correct Answer":"L4-5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient is due to undergoing ligation of SFJ for varicose veins. An artery was injured causing brisk bleeding: what is the artery to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Superficial external pudendal artery",
        "Option 2":"Femoral artery",
        "Option 3":"Deep external pudendal artery",
        "Option 4":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Deep external pudendal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the most commonly injured ligament in ankle injury?",
        "Option 1":"Posterior talofibular ligament",
        "Option 2":"Deltoid ligament",
        "Option 3":"Calcaneofibular ligament",
        "Option 4":"Anterior talofibular ligament",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterior talofibular ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 54 years old man undergone hip replacement for fractured neck femur. During follow up,  the man walks with the Trendelenburg gait. what is the most likely cause?",
        "Option 1":"Sciatic nerve injury",
        "Option 2":"Gluteus Medius muscle paralysis",
        "Option 3":"Femoral nerve injury",
        "Option 4":"Gluteus maximus muscle paralysis",
        "Option 5":"Inferior gluteal nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Gluteus Medius muscle paralysis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During posterior hip approach for a fractured neck of femur, there was brisk bleeding and the  surgeon tried to control the bleeder with ligation Which blood vessel is mostly injured?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral artery",
        "Option 2":"Superior gluteal artery",
        "Option 3":"Inferior gluteal artery",
        "Option 4":"Saphenous vein",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior gluteal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following muscle is a hip abductor?",
        "Option 1":"Pyriformis",
        "Option 2":"Semitendinosus",
        "Option 3":"Sartorius",
        "Option 4":"Gluteus medius",
        "Option 5":"Obturator internus",
        "Correct Answer":"Gluteus medius"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man developed a groin swelling which is reducible and gives minimal expansile impulse on  cough. On examination, the swelling was found to be lateral to the pubic tubercle. What is the  most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral hernia",
        "Option 2":"Hydrocele",
        "Option 3":"Inguinal hernia",
        "Option 4":"Femoral pseudoaneurysm",
        "Option 5":"Inguinal lymph node",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral hernia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A surgeon is performing iliac LN dissection for a metastatic ovarian cancer. During operation he adversely injured a nerve emerging at the lateral aspect of psoas major muscle. The patient suffered loss of sensation over the lateral aspect of the thigh. What is the name of this nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh",
        "Option 3":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 4":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sural nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient developed sensory deficit aver the anterior thigh with inability to extend the knee after surgical hernia repair. What is the nerve injured?",
        "Option 1":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 2":"Lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh",
        "Option 3":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 4":"Femoral branch of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following muscles is a hip external rotator?",
        "Option 1":"Gluteus maximus",
        "Option 2":"Gluteus Medius",
        "Option 3":"Gracilis",
        "Option 4":"Adductor magnus",
        "Option 5":"Obturator internus",
        "Correct Answer":"Obturator internus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient suffered a gunshot injury to the back of his distal thigh. During wound exploration  the surgeon inadeptly injured a structure which is located laterally. What is most lateral structure in the popliteal fossa?",
        "Option 1":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Popliteal vein",
        "Option 3":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 4":"Common peroneal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sural nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Common peroneal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During short saphenous vein striping, what is the most liable nerve to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 2":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Superficial peroneal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Sural nerve",
        "Option 5":"Lateral plantar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Sural nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which spinal root is responsible for ankle reflex?",
        "Option 1":"L1,L2,L3",
        "Option 2":"L5,S1,S2",
        "Option 3":"S2,S3,S4",
        "Option 4":"L1,L4,L5",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"L5,S1,S2"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which bone is in direct contact with navicular bone?",
        "Option 1":"1st metatarsal bone",
        "Option 2":"3rd metatarsal bone",
        "Option 3":"Cuneiforms",
        "Option 4":"2nd metatarsal bone",
        "Option 5":"Lateral 2 metatarsals",
        "Correct Answer":"Cuneiforms"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Cuboid bone articulates with",
        "Option 1":"Talus and lateral two metatarsals",
        "Option 2":"Calcaneus and lateral two metatarsals",
        "Option 3":"Calcaneus and lateral three metatarsals",
        "Option 4":"Talus and medial two metatarsals",
        "Option 5":"Navicular and lateral two metatarsals",
        "Correct Answer":"Calcaneus and lateral two metatarsals"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the action of iliopsoas muscle?",
        "Option 1":"Knee flexion",
        "Option 2":"Hip extension",
        "Option 3":"Hip adduction",
        "Option 4":"Hip flexion",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Hip flexion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 years old man suffered parathesia over the lateral aspect of the thigh after a car accident.  What is the spinal nerve root of the responsible nerve?",
        "Option 1":"L1-2",
        "Option 2":"L2-3",
        "Option 3":"L3-4",
        "Option 4":"L3 alone",
        "Option 5":"L2-4",
        "Correct Answer":"L2-3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45-year-old man presents with fever and pain in his right loin and groin. A soft swelling was noted in his femoral triangle. Diagnosis of a psoas abscess was made. Which of the following statements is most accurate regarding psoas major?",
        "Option 1":"It arises from the lateral borders of the bodies of T12 to L5",
        "Option 2":"It extends the hip",
        "Option 3":"It inserts into the greater trochanter of the femur",
        "Option 4":"It is innervated Irom T12 and L1",
        "Option 5":"It passes posterior to the capsule of the hip joint",
        "Correct Answer":"It arises from the lateral borders of the bodies of T12 to L5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 34-year-old man is seen in the Emergency Department with a fibular fracture following football match On examination he is noted to have loss of foot eversion. Which area of skin should be examined to confirm loss of the cutaneous distribution of the affected nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Along the lateral aspect of the foot",
        "Option 2":"Along the medial aspect of the foot",
        "Option 3":"Cross the dorsal surface of the foot",
        "Option 4":"On the plantar Surface of the foot",
        "Option 5":"Over the heel",
        "Correct Answer":"Cross the dorsal surface of the foot"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 78- year-old woman presents with urinary urgency and incontinence. The external urethral sphincter is innervated by which of the following nerve roots?",
        "Option 1":"L3,4&5",
        "Option 2":"L4,5&S1",
        "Option 3":"L5,S1& 2",
        "Option 4":"S1,2&3",
        "Option 5":"S2,3&4",
        "Correct Answer":"S2,3&4"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 36 years old suffered a complex fracture of fibular neck. Which nerve is at risk?",
        "Option 1":"Sural nerve",
        "Option 2":"Common peroneal",
        "Option 3":"Deep peroneal",
        "Option 4":"Superficial peroneal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Common peroneal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient was stabbed in his buttock during a fight. On examination he has a deep wound with  loss of plantar flexion of his foot and toes with normal dorsiflexion. What is the most likely  injured structure?",
        "Option 1":"Common peroneal component of sciatic nerve",
        "Option 2":"Pudendal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Tibial component of sciatic nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sural nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Tibial component of sciatic nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A middle-aged man was involved in a motorboat accident, he sustained a separation of lumbar  spine from sacral spine, with associated nerve root injury. Which of the following movements  will be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Hip flexion",
        "Option 2":"Knee extension",
        "Option 3":"Foot inversion",
        "Option 4":"Plantar flexion",
        "Option 5":"Hip adduction",
        "Correct Answer":"Plantar flexion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During posterior approach to the distal femur. Which nerve is at risk?",
        "Option 1":"Common peroneal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 4":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Tibial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 30-year-old man is involved in a road traffic accident and sustains a dislocation of the knee  This is reduced under anaesthesia and immobilized in a cast. He was given a sciatic nerve block  and has a painless and pulseless limb. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Compartment syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Femoral nerve injury",
        "Option 3":"Femoral artery injury",
        "Option 4":"Sciatic nerve injury",
        "Option 5":"Popliteal artery injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Popliteal artery injury"
    },
    {
        "Question":"76 years old woman dislocates her total hip replacement whilst bending down. This is reduced under general anaesthesia. Following, the operation, she is unable to dorsiflex her foot. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve injury",
        "Option 2":"Plaster sores",
        "Option 3":"Popliteal artery injury",
        "Option 4":"Sciatic nerve injury",
        "Option 5":"Tibial nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Sciatic nerve injury"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the spinal route value of tibial nerve?",
        "Option 1":"L4-S3",
        "Option 2":"L2-4",
        "Option 3":"S2,3,4",
        "Option 4":"L3,4",
        "Option 5":"L2,3",
        "Correct Answer":"L4-S3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Posterior leg compartment syndrome can be diagnosed by pain on passive:",
        "Option 1":"Hallux flexion",
        "Option 2":"Hallux extension",
        "Option 3":"Ankle planter flexion",
        "Option 4":"Eversion",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Hallux extension"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 years old man suffered numbness over the inferomedial aspect of the leg just below the knee. Which nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Sural nerve",
        "Option 2":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Infrapatellar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Superficial peroneal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Infrapatellar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 30-year-old man presents to the clinic with intermittent pain and paraesthesia in his right upper lateral thigh. This was found to be due to entrapment of the lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh. Which of the following is the most accurate description of its anatomy?",
        "Option 1":"It is formed by fibers from L1 and L2 and emerges on the anterior surface of the psoas muscle",
        "Option 2":"It is formed by fibers from L2 and L3 and emerges on the lateral border of the psoas muscle",
        "Option 3":"It is formed by fibers from L2, L3 and L4 and emerges on the lateral border of the psoas muscle",
        "Option 4":"It is formed by fibers from L2, L3 and L4 and emerges on the medial border of the psoas muscle",
        "Option 5":"It is formed by fibers from L3 and L4 and emerges on the medial border of the psoas muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"It is formed by fibers from L2 and L3 and emerges on the lateral border of the psoas muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In the leg, which of the following structures is in closest proximity to the middle of the fibula and at risk in fibulectomy?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior tibial artery",
        "Option 2":"Deep peroneal (fibular) nerve",
        "Option 3":"Peroneal (fibular) artery",
        "Option 4":"Posterior tibial artery",
        "Option 5":"Tibial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Peroneal (fibular) artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 26-year-old soccer player twists his ankle. The lateral side of the joint is tender, bruised and  swolen. The medial side is normal, Radiograph shows no bony injury. What is the most  commony injured 2 ankle ligaments?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior talofibular ligament and calcaneofibular ligament",
        "Option 2":"Anterior talofibular ligament and deltoid ligament",
        "Option 3":"Anterior talofibular ligament and spring ligament",
        "Option 4":"Deltoid ligament and interosseus membrane",
        "Option 5":"Posterior talofibular ligament and deltoid ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterior talofibular ligament and calcaneofibular ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 44-year-old man with HIV has a large abscess along the lateral border of psoas major muscle  causing pressure on the nerves that exit the muscle in this region. On examination of his lower  limb, which of the following features is likely to be found?",
        "Option 1":"Loss of sensation on the lateral aspect of the lower leg",
        "Option 2":"Meralgia parasthetica",
        "Option 3":"Loss of sensation on the sole of the foot",
        "Option 4":"Weakness of hip abduction",
        "Option 5":"Weakness of hip adduction",
        "Correct Answer":"Meralgia parasthetica"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year-old woman undergoes intramedullary nailing for a tibial fracture. Twelve hours  postoperatively, she develops severe pain in the leg. Motor function is difficult to assess and  there is numbness in the web space between the great toe and the second toe. In which  compartment is compartment syndrome most likely?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior leg compartment",
        "Option 2":"Deep compartment of the foot",
        "Option 3":"Deep posterior leg compartment",
        "Option 4":"Lateral leg compartment",
        "Option 5":"Superficial posterior leg compartment",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterior leg compartment"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45 years old man is involved in a road traffic accident. On assessment, his general condition is stable. An entry wound is noted on the posterolateral aspect of the left thigh and an X-ray reveals a bullet adjacent to the femur. He is not able to move his left toes or ankle. Which of the following is the most likely nerve lesion?",
        "Option 1":"S1 root lesion",
        "Option 2":"L5 root lesion",
        "Option 3":"Deep peroneal nerve palsy",
        "Option 4":"Sciatic nerve palsy",
        "Option 5":"Tibial nerve palsy",
        "Correct Answer":"Sciatic nerve palsy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient is unable to medially rotate the thigh. What is the affected nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Superior gluteal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Inferior gluteal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 4":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Option 5":"Pudendal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior gluteal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is a hip adductor?",
        "Option 1":"Gluteus Medius",
        "Option 2":"Semitendinosus",
        "Option 3":"Biceps femoris",
        "Option 4":"Gracilis",
        "Option 5":"Sartorius",
        "Correct Answer":"Gracilis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 years old patient presented with back pain. On examination, he has lateral foot  numbness, with weakness in dorsiflexion of the ankle and Hallux Physical examination revealed intact ankle and knee jerk reflexes, Which nerve root is the cause?",
        "Option 1":"Compression of L5",
        "Option 2":"L3,L4 compression",
        "Option 3":"L4,L5",
        "Option 4":"S1-2",
        "Option 5":"S1 only",
        "Correct Answer":"Compression of L5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"While you are doing a total knee replacement using a saw, what is the most important  structure to worry about?",
        "Option 1":"Medial & lateral collaterals arteries",
        "Option 2":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 3":"Common fibular nerve",
        "Option 4":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Profunda femoris artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Popliteal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient suffered a bullet injury entering from anterolateral aspect of the thigh to the groin.  He cannot straight his leg as a result, What is the most likely injured nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superior gluteal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Obturator nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An incision is made at the marked line on the  picture. This incision is most likely to cause injury of which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Saphenous nerve",
        "Option 2":"Tibial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Lateral planter nerve",
        "Option 4":"Lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh",
        "Option 5":"Sural nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Sural nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structure passes below the piriformis in the greater sciatic notch?",
        "Option 1":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 2":"Tendon of obturator internus",
        "Option 3":"Superior gluteal artery",
        "Option 4":"Nerve to obturator internus",
        "Option 5":"Obturator externus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Nerve to obturator internus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the surface anatomy to take a sample from femoral artery?",
        "Option 1":"A point midway between anterior inferior iliac spine and symphysis pubis",
        "Option 2":"A point midway between anterior inferior iliac spine and pubic tubercle",
        "Option 3":"Midpoint of inguinal hernia",
        "Option 4":"Mid-inguinal point",
        "Option 5":"2 cm below and lateral to pubic tubercle",
        "Correct Answer":"Mid-inguinal point"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43 years old man presented after a road traffic accident with flexed and internally rotated thigh. Examination revealed absent sensation below the knee except for the medial aspect Which of the following is the most likely causative injury?",
        "Option 1":"Fracture shaft of femur",
        "Option 2":"Anterior dislocation of the hip",
        "Option 3":"Supracondylar fracture of femur",
        "Option 4":"Posterior dislocation of the hip",
        "Option 5":"Fracture neck of femur",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior dislocation of the hip"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 33 years old female suffered a lower limb injury during an RTA Examination revealed loss of all movements below the knee level, Xray revealed a fractured pelvis with suspected sciatic injury at the level of its pelvic exit. Which of the following is the commonest description of this level?",
        "Option 1":"Tibial component exits inferior to pyriformis and common peroneal nerve pierces the muscle.",
        "Option 2":"Tibial component exits inferior to pyriformis and common peroneal superior to the muscle.",
        "Option 3":"Both components exit within a common connective tissue sheath inferior to pyriformis.",
        "Option 4":"Both components exit within a common connective tissue sheath superior to pyriformis.",
        "Option 5":"Common peroneal component exits inferior to pyriformis and tibial nerve pierces the muscle.",
        "Correct Answer":"Both components exit within a common connective tissue sheath inferior to pyriformis."
    },
    {
        "Question":"Inguinal Ligament forms the superior border of which of the following landmarks?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral triangle",
        "Option 2":"Femoral canal",
        "Option 3":"Inguinal canal",
        "Option 4":"Sub sartorial canal",
        "Option 5":"Popliteal fossa",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral triangle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45 years old man is involved in a fight while he suffered a stab to the buttock. On assessment, his general condition is stable. An entry wound is noted on the posterolateral aspect of the left thigh He is not able to move his left toes or ankle. Sensory loss affecting all the leg and foot except medial aspect of the leg- Which of the following actions is likely to be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Knee extension",
        "Option 2":"Hip flexion",
        "Option 3":"Thigh adduction",
        "Option 4":"Thigh abduction",
        "Option 5":"Knee flexion",
        "Correct Answer":"Knee flexion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which one of the following nerves passes on the anterior surface of iliopsoas muscle?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh",
        "Option 3":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 4":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Genitofemoral nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 23 years old poliomyelitis patient was examined in the orthopaedic clinic for follow up. On examination the patient has foot drop, Which of the following muscles is mostly responsible for this deformity?",
        "Option 1":"Flexor digitorum",
        "Option 2":"Extensor digitorum brevis",
        "Option 3":"Tibialis anterior",
        "Option 4":"Gastrocnemius",
        "Option 5":"Extensor hallucis brevis",
        "Correct Answer":"Tibialis anterior"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 52 years old lifter presented to the clinic with back pain. Disc prolapse was detected on MRI On examination, the patient has lost dorsiflexion of the foot and hallux extension. Sensation was lost over the hallux and dorsum of the foot extending to the lateral leg. Which nerve root would be compressed?",
        "Option 1":"L4-5",
        "Option 2":"L5.S1",
        "Option 3":"S1-2",
        "Option 4":"L3-4",
        "Option 5":"L4 alone",
        "Correct Answer":"L4-5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43 year old man suffered a leg trauma during a fight. Investigations revealed a fracture tibia and fibula with widening of the space between them. What is the type of joint between the tibia and the?",
        "Option 1":"Syndesmosis",
        "Option 2":"Plane",
        "Option 3":"Ellipsoid",
        "Option 4":"Hinge",
        "Option 5":"Ball and socket synovial",
        "Correct Answer":"Syndesmosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During a hip surgery, an orthopaedic surgeon tried to release iliopsoas muscle near its insertion to the lesser trochanter of femur Which structure is at risk?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Femoral artery",
        "Option 3":"Femoral vein",
        "Option 4":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Option 5":"Medial circumflex artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial circumflex artery"
    }
]